andrei@linux.com andreipetre.ro

## Objective

After having worked full-stack for 5 years, I'm looking for some low level programming opportunities. In addition, I've got 1.5 years C++ experience as a TA in university and an interest in open source, python, linux, rock climbing and chess; check my website for more. I'm also a member of ROSEdu, an organization that promotes open-source in education.

## Experience

Software Engineer, UpbeatPR, San Francisco, CA

Feb 2015 - present

Highly targeted pitching process, enabled through our amounts of data we collected about journalists – PR without relationships.

- One of the first engineers at Upbeat, designed and built systems core to our business in Python, Django, Scrapy, Celery, ElasticSearch, Javascript (ES6), React, Redux and Ruby on Rails
- Worked on all parts of delivering software: design, implementation, testing, deployment, continuous integration, maintenance, instrumentation and monitoring.
- Worked remotely <sup>2</sup>/<sub>3</sub> of my time at Upbeat, but, in spite of that, was able to become an asset to the team, helping my colleagues grow through well-thought and in-depth code reviews. Maintainer of our scraping system and of our data quality efforts.

## Selected accomplishments

- $\bullet$  Implemented an indexing system using ElasticSearch, that powered an internal search engine that our PR agents used to pitch journalists our primary business driver. We've indexed  ${\sim}16\mathrm{M}$  articles in ElasticSearch.
- Designed and built a cost-effective FeedPoller system that had daily volume of ~650K new urls per day from 20K feeds we had in our db. It was able to poll the feeds efficiently, each worker could handle hundreds of urls over a few seconds, doing asynchronous requests with a combination of gevent and celery. The system could easily scale horizontally.

## Software Engineer, dev.Label

Aug 2014 - Jan 2015

Full stack developer, used Groovy, Javascript, Coffeescript and ChromeDriver for working on trade.it, a multi-broker trading application, while in its early development stage.

**Teaching Assistant**, POLITEHNICA University of Bucharest 2013 – 2014, 2016 – 2017 Taught Data Structures & Algorithms class for 3 years, using C++. Also taught 3 other classes: Object Oriented Programming, Functional Programming and Complexity Analysis of Algorithms.

**Software Engineer**, UberVU (acquired by HootSuite, ~15M\$)

Jun 2012 – Sept 2013 Social media analytics, monitoring and engaging dashboard.

- Started working at uberVU while still in college, and picked up best practices and new technologies I've never worked with before with tremendous speed.
- First as a Frontend Engineer, working on our own mozaic.JS (backbone.js based) framework that enabled the new interface that would lead to the acquisition of uberVU, just 4 months after my leave
- Then also working on the REST API for the JS frontend, using Django, Tastypie and mySQL
- Finally, worked on the Python backend pipeline that collected and indexed data into MongoDB and ElasticSearch, as well as on our CI system and deployment scripts

Education

BSc, Major in Engineering and Computer Science

Oct 2010 - July 2014

University POLITEHNICA of Bucharest, Romania Faculty of Automatic Control and Computer Science

Skills In Production: Python, Django, Flask, ElasticSearch, mongo, Scrapy, Celery

JS, nodeJS, React, Redux, CoffeeScript, jQuery, Backbone.js Git, Bash shell scripting, Heroku, PostgreSQL, ChromeDriver

Groovy, Grails, Ruby on Rails

In TA classes: C++, Java

In open source course: C & GObject for Anjuta, a Gnome IDE, during an open source

course, CDL

In General: Go, Scheme, Haskell, Prolog

Certifications: Linux (LPIC-1)